<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.elhombretecla.GifForge</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <name>GIF Forge</name>
  <summary>Record your screen and edit it into an optimized GIF or video</summary>

  <description>
    <p>
      GIF Forge is a modern Linux screen-capture studio. Record a region,
      window or screen on Wayland or X11, then refine the result on a timeline —
      trim, cut, reorder, retime and crop — before exporting an optimized GIF,
      WebM video or APNG.
    </p>
    <p>It keeps recording simple while adding powerful frame-by-frame editing:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Record a region, window or the whole screen</li>
      <li>Native Wayland capture via the screen-cast portal, plus X11</li>
      <li>Frame-by-frame timeline: delete, duplicate, reorder and reverse frames</li>
      <li>Remove duplicate frames and reduce frame count</li>
      <li>Adjust per-frame delay and change playback speed</li>
      <li>Trim to a selection and crop the frame</li>
      <li>Undo and redo every edit</li>
      <li>Export optimized GIF, WebM or APNG</li>
      <li>Save and reopen editable projects, with crash recovery</li>
      <li>HiDPI aware, light and dark themes</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.elhombretecla.GifForge.desktop</launchable>

  <provides>
    <binary>gif-forge</binary>
  </provides>

  <categories>
    <category>Graphics</category>
    <category>AudioVideo</category>
  </categories>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>screencast</keyword>
    <keyword>screen recorder</keyword>
    <keyword>GIF</keyword>
    <keyword>editor</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>

  <developer id="io.github.elhombretecla">
    <name>GIF Forge contributors</name>
  </developer>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/elhombretecla/gif-forge</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/elhombretecla/gif-forge/issues</url>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.1.2" date="2026-06-11">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes single-frame "wallpaper flashes" in recordings made on X11
        under a compositing desktop (seen on GNOME Shell with NVIDIA): glitch
        frames the capture race produces are now detected and repaired before
        export. Also fixes GIF exports playing with uneven frame timing
        (120/80 ms instead of the edited 100 ms delays).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.1" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Fixes the capture region showing as opaque grey — and recording a
        single frozen frame — on X11 sessions without a compositor. The region
        is now a real see-through hole, so the desktop shows through with or
        without compositing.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.1.0" date="2026-06-01">
      <description>
        <p>First release: Wayland-first recorder, timeline editor with undo/redo,
        optimized GIF/WebM/APNG export, editable projects with crash recovery, a
        localized UI (English/Spanish/French/German/Portuguese), and packages for
        Flatpak, AppImage, .deb, Arch and Fedora.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
